12.1話「ばすてき」
Episode 12.1 "Bus-ish"
ではお前達、これを見つけてくるのです。
And so, you girls are going to look for this.
曲がってない奴を見つけてくるのですよ。
One that isn't bent.
このまま付けるんじゃダメなのか？
What's wrong with using that one?
とりあえず、船にはできる、って聞いたよー。
｛I heard that it can be made into a boat.｝
陸地を走る時に必要なのです。
It is necessary when driving on land.
頭を使うのです。
Use your head.
ちゃんと食べるのですか。
Have you been eating properly?
グヌヌ…！アライさんはその辺ばっちりなのだ！
｛｝! Arai-san always does!
かばんさんの為ならどんとこいだけどさー。
Although you're always ready if it's for Kaban-san.
それって、どこにあるのー？
Where do we find those?
似たようなバスは、いくつか島で目撃されているのです。
Similar buses have been spotted around the island.
まずはそれを探すのです。
Start by looking for those.
探すのです。
For those.
ちゃんとこれが、真ん丸かどうか、よく見るのですよ。
Look closely and make sure that this is round.
任せるのだ！ピッカピカのを見つけてくるのだ！
Leave it to Arai-san! I'll find you a really clean one!
あー、でもアライさーん、ここんとこ歩きすぎたよー。
Ah, but you've been walking too much lately, Arai-san.
サンドスターがもう…
Your Sandstar is already…
しょうがないですね。遊園地にバス的な物があるのです。
It can't be helped. There is a bus-ish thing at the amusement park.
バス的な物を貸してやるのです。
We'll lend a bus-ish thing to you girls.
とっとと行くのです。
Come along now.
何ぃ！？アライさんもバスに乗れるのか！？
Huh!? You mean, Arai-san gets to ride on a bus too!?
おー、よかったねー、アライさーん。
Oh, how nice, Arai-san.
おー！
Ooh!
すごーいねー。
Impressive.
お前らにはそうですね。これぐらいがいいのです。
This should be about the right size for you girls.
これくらいなら、足が届くのです。お前らは小さいので。
Your feet should be able to reach the pedals if it's this big, since you girls are small.
ハカセ・ジョシュと似たようなもんだよー。
Just like you two.
おー！
Ooh!
わっせ、わっせ、わっせ…
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho…
出発！…なのだ！
Let's go!
はーいよ、っと。
Mm.
わっせ、わっせ、わっせ…
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho…
歩くのとそんなに変わらないのです。
It's really not that different from walking.
あれは船出に間に合いますか、ハカセ。
Do you think they'll make it before they set sail?
まあ、なんだかんだ。あの根性を信用してるのです。
I think they'll get it done. I trust in their spirit.
大丈夫ですよ、ジョシュ。
It'll be alright, Assistant.
これで概ね片付きましたね。
This should be the last of it.
まったく。長も楽じゃないのです。
Goodness. It's not easy being a chief.
これで長らしく果報を食べて待てるのです。まったく。
I suppose all we can do now is ｛｝. Goodness.
今日もかばんにご馳走になりますか。ハカセ。
Will we be partaking of Kaban's cooking again? Professor.
そうですね。ちょっと料理を引っ掛けて帰りますか、ジョシュ。
Indeed. Shall we go to oversee it?